Hopefully you found this super satisfying to be able to have this nice business result and have it calling
이런 멋진 비즈니스 결과를 얻고 LLM을 두 번 호출하는 것에 대해 아주 만족스러우시길 바랍니다
an LLM twice, we can make this result a little bit more satisfying by adding in something called streaming,
스트리밍이라는 걸 추가함으로써 이 결과를 좀 더 만족스럽게 만들 수 있어요 아주
which is so common that you see in these tools that we've experienced ourselves in the chat user interfaces
흔한 거죠 채팅에서 경험한 이런 도구에서 볼 수 있습니다 사용자 인터페이스와
and streaming is when the information flows back from the LLM and appears in what they call the typewriter
스트리밍 채팅에서 정보가 LLM에서 다시 흘러와 타자기 스타일 인터페이스로 나타날
style interface.
때죠
And the way you do it is remarkably simple.
그 방법은 놀랍도록 간단해요
Uh, when you are creating your, uh, call to OpenAI chat completions, create, uh, if you want to
오픈AI 채팅 완료를 위한 호출을 만들 때 생성할 때 한 번에 다 받고 싶진 않지만 다시
not just receive it all back in one go, but you want it to flow back, you simply pass in another parameter
흘러가길 원한다면 다른 매개 변수 스트림을 참으로
stream equals true.
넘기면 되죠
We'll find when we go and use Claude that it has a slightly different API, but this is one of the rare
클로드를 사용할 때 API가 약간 다른 걸 알게 될 겁니다 하지만 GPT와
times when GPT and Claude are a bit different.
클로드가 약간 다른 건 드문 경우죠
But that's how you do it with GPT stream equals true.
GPT 스트리밍 = True에선 이렇게 하는 거예요
Now what does that mean?
그게 무슨 뜻이죠?
What it means is that what comes back into stream is no longer the the single text response, but instead
스트림으로 돌아온 것은 더 이상 단일 텍스트 응답이 아니라 반복할
you get back something that you can iterate over, and as you iterate over, each chunk of the response
수 있는 것을 얻게 됩니다 반복을 하면 각 응답 덩어리가 나타납니다
will come through, um, and you can just sort of say for chunk in stream print chunk.
스트림 프린트 덩어리를 선택하는 거죠
Now, in our case, we want to be a little bit smarter than that because we're we're showing this in
우리 경우엔 그것보다 좀 더 영리해야 해요 왜냐하면 마크다운 비트로 이걸
markdown.
보여주니까요
Um, and actually it's a little tiny bit fiddly because markdown is something where the, the markdown
사실 좀 성가신 일이에요 마크다운이란 마크다운 캐릭터를 스트림으로
characters, you might it might start to stream some markdown characters, and you would then need it
만들 때 그걸 화면에 포함시켜야 하거든요
So there's a bit of hokey code here to handle the fact that we're going to want to rewrite the full
여기 호키 코드가 좀 있네요 각 비트에 대해 전체 마크다운 버전을 다시 써야 한다는 사실을
markdown version for each chunk so you can look through it.
처리하기 위해서요 여러분이 살펴볼 수 있게요
But basically I keep a sort of running track of everything in response, a kind of cumulative track
기본적으로는 모든 것에 대한 대응을 위한 트랙을 유지해요 모든 덩크가
of all of the chunks that have come back.
누적된 트랙을 만드는 거죠
And so for each chunk that comes back, I basically, uh, include that in response.
그래서 저는 답변을 받을 때마다 그 부분을 포함해요
Uh, I strip out if the word markdown is actually in there, I strip it out of the response.
실제로 마크다운이라는 단어가 있으면 그 단어는 반응에서 제거해요
And finally I update the full display to show that.
마지막으로 전체 디스플레이를 업데이트해 보여드릴게요
So this is all a little bit complex.
비트 코드는 좀 복잡해요
You wouldn't need this if you were just simply writing text.
그냥 글만 쓰면 이런 건 필요 없잖아요
Uh, the only reason that you need it this way is because we want to show it in a nice, fancy markdown
이렇게 해야 하는 이유는 멋지게 줄이는 방식으로 보여주고 싶어서예요
And let me show you what I mean by that.
무슨 뜻인지 보여 드릴게요
If we now repeat this for anthropic, we'll have to wait a minute while it, uh, while it does that
이걸 anthropic에서 반복하면 1분 기다려야 합니다 링크를 먼저
first finding the links and getting all these pages, and then here you go.
찾고 이 페이지들을 다 얻을 때까지요 이제 됐네요
Look at that.
보세요
It's the familiar streaming interface that you can see there, and it's done.
익숙한 스트리밍 인터페이스죠 다 됐어요
And I love the fact that because it's markdown, we also get things like the links in here.
마크다운이 되어 있어서 링크 같은 것도 get이 된다는 게 좋아요
And just to show you what I was talking about.
제가 말하던 걸 보여드릴게요
If you didn't want to have it displaying in markdown, the simpler way that you could do this is that
마크다운에서 디스플레이하는 걸 원치 않는 경우 더 간단한
you could have it say like, uh, something like, um, for chunk in stream.
방법은 스트림에서의 청크를 위한 것 같은 걸 하는 거죠
Uh, print chunk.
한 덩어리 인쇄해요
And then we'd have to have something like end equals that stops it from printing a new line each time.
그런 다음 end = 같은 걸 해야 합니다 매번 새 줄을 프린트하는 걸 멈추도록요
And I think this is now let's see if that works.
제 생각엔 이게∙∙∙ 작동하는지 보죠
Uh, this this would now just print it as a series of, uh, little, uh, pieces of text so we won't
이건 그냥 일련의 텍스트 조각으로 프린트할 거예요 마크다운 포맷이 안 나오게요
get the markdown formatting.
Get up
Oh, that's not going to work.
그건 안 돼요
Uh, sorry.
미안해요
This should of course, be chunk.
이건 당연히 청크죠
I might as well put in all of this like that.
그냥 이렇게 다 얹는 게 낫겠어요
Otherwise, we're getting the objects that are flowing back.
안 그러면 물체가 뒤로 흐르거든요
You probably saw me doing that and thought, idiot, there we go.
제가 이러는 걸 보고 바보라고 생각하셨겠죠
It shows you this is real time.
실시간이란 걸 보여주죠
Uh, okay, let's try that again.
네, 다시 해 보죠
See if we get a better result now.
Get it, get it, get it, get it, it, it, it! 이제 더 좋은 결과가 나오는지 보죠
So if we simply put in here the the the the the print statement.
여기에 입력하면∙∙∙ print 문을요
Like this.
이렇게요
Then what you'll see coming back.
다시 보게 될 거예요
Here you go.
여기요
You see it comes back.
다시 돌아오죠
It's super simple.
아주 간단해요
It just won't be nicely formatted.
서식이 별로일 뿐이죠
But obviously the code, if you do it this way is really simple.
하지만 코드는 이렇게 하면 정말 간단해요
This is all the code you need to be able to stream back results.
결과를 스트리밍하는 데 필요한 모든 코드예요
So you set stream equals true and then you iterate back that way.
스트리밍 = true를 설정하면 그 방법으로 반복되죠
Uh, so now let me remove that and I will uncomment this if you don't know by the way then then a command
이제 저걸 제거하고 주석을 제거하겠습니다 여러분이 모르신다면 command와 나눗셈 기호 혹은 Windows에서
and the divide by sign or on the windows it's a windows key and divide by sign, uh is something which
Windows 키와 나눗셈 기호는 코드 블록의 주석을 제거하거나 주석을 제거하는
will comment out or uncomment a block of code like that.
것이죠
It's a useful shortcut to know, uh, all right, let's run this again and just see anthropic one more
유용한 지름길이죠 이걸 다시 실행해 근사한 서식이 있는
time with the nice great formatting.
athropic을 한 번 더 보죠
Finds the links.
연결 고리를 찾죠
And here it is again.
또 나오네요
And of course it's going to be amazingly a different brochure every time.
물론 매번 다른 브로슈어가 있어요
Uh, and, uh, there it is this time.
이번엔 그렇게 됐네요
And now let's try a different company.
이제 다른 회사를 알아보죠
Let's try hugging face the ubiquitous open source platform for, uh, AI engineers.
인공지능 엔지니어를 위한 유비쿼털 오픈 소스 플랫폼을 안아보죠
Let's see how we get.
get get 해 볼게요
We get some links.
Get it 링크도 있네요
And here comes the hugging face brochure with career opportunities.
이제 안아주는 얼굴 책자가 나오네요
Perks.
특전이죠
Get in touch.
Get it 연락 주세요
And then.
그리고요
And together, let's build the future of AI.
함께 인공지능의 미래를 만들어 나가요
Very nice.
아주 좋아요
All right, let's do one more thing to make this fun.
좋아요, 더 재미있게 한 가지 더 해보죠
Let's just go all the way back to where we created the system prompt.
시스템 프롬프트를 생성했던 곳으로 돌아가보죠
Where was that?
어디서요?
All the way back here.
저 뒤쪽에서요
System prompt.
시스템 프롬프트예요
So one of the things about the system prompt is that this is the place where you not only describe the
시스템 프롬프트의 특징 중 하나는 완료될 작업을 설명하는
task that is to be done, but also you talk about the tone and character that the LLM should adopt in
곳일 뿐 아니라 톤과 문자에도 대해 얘기합니다 LLM이 콘텐츠를 생성할 때 채택해야
generating this content.
하는 거죠
So let's comment this and uncomment a variation right here.
이걸 주석 처리하고 변형을 해제하죠
And this variation just includes that.
이 변형에는 그런 게 포함되죠
It should be a short, humorous, entertaining, jokey brochure and we will run that code.
짧고, 유머러스하고, 재미있고, 농담조의 브로슈어여야 해요 그 코드를 실행하죠
Uh, and because I use very naughtily here, system prompt is like a global variable that I refer to
여기서 아주 노골적으로 사용하기 때문에 System 프롬프트는 다른 곳에서도 언급하는 전역 변수
elsewhere.
같아요
So I do believe I don't need to rerun any of this because I have that like hardcoded, I should be able
이걸 재실행할 필요는 없어요 하드코딩이 돼 있으니까요
to come all the way down here and just simply rerun this.
여기까지 와서 이걸 그냥 재실행하면 되죠
And I believe, if I'm not mistaken, that we're now going to get a jovial, jokey ha ha, here we go.
제 생각이 맞는다면 이제 아주 유쾌하고 재미있는 장면이 나올 거예요 get it get it
Welcome to anthropic, where I gets a safety net.
안전망이 있는 안드로픽에 잘 오셨어요
Uh, at anthropic, we're building AI systems you can actually trust, ensuring they're more reliable
앤스로픽에서는 여러분이 믿을 수 있는 인공지능 시스템을 개발합니다 모닝커피보다
than your morning coffee, and easier to understand than your cats mood swings.
더 신뢰할 수 있고 고양이 감정의 변화보다 이해하기 쉽도록요
Based on sunny land of San Francisco, we're on a mission to make AI a friend, not a foe.
샌프란시스코의 햇살 나라에서는 인공지능을 적이 아닌 친구로 만들려 하죠
So, I mean, it's just It's extraordinary that by making a small change to the system prompt like that,
즉각적으로 시스템을 약간 변경했을 뿐인데 이렇게 완전히 다른
we can have such a wonderfully different lens on our company brochure.
회사 브로슈어를 만들 수 있다니 정말 놀라워요
I find that just just really, truly remarkable.
정말 놀라운 일이에요
I will uncomment I will comment that so that it doesn't confuse you when you see it.
주석 제거∙∙∙ 주석을 달겠습니다 여러분이 혼란스러워하지 않도록요
But um, this of course lends me to the first thing I want to say, which is that as you experiment
이 기회에 이 말을 하고 싶네요 이 실험을 통해 여러분이 깊이 이해할 수 있는 기회가
with this, this is your opportunity to really understand deeply what it means to use prompting to affect
될 겁니다 어떤 작품이 탄생하든 프롬프트를 통해 개성에 영향을 준다는 게 어떤
the character of what's generated.
의미인지 말이죠
So you can take it a step further.
한 단계 더 나아갈 수 있게요
Make a snarky brochure that's loaded with sarcasm.
비꼬는 내용으로 책자를 만들어 봐요
Make a brochure in Spanish.
스페인어로 책자를 만들어요
Uh, do add something that will that will translate to a different language.
다른 언어로 번역할 수 있는 것도 추가해 주세요
Uh, try all of these different things.
다양한 걸 시도해 보는 거죠
Um, and this is, this will be very important part of learning how you use prompting to affect the
이건 아주 중요한 부분이에요 어떻게 프롬프트해서 결과에 영향을 주는지를 학습하는 데 있어서요
type of result that you get.
Get up
Okay, let me wrap this up before we start talking about too much about exercises.
좋아요, 운동 얘기를 너무 많이 하기 전에 그만 끝내죠
So what we did today was we extended what we did in day one instead of just calling one LM call to summarize
오늘 우리가 한 건 첫날에 한 걸 확장했어요 웹 사이트를 요약하기 위해 LM 호출을
a website, we ended up making two calls to LM one to collect relevant links and one to then from a
하나 하는 대신 LM 1에 두 번 호출해 관련 링크를 수집하고 그 모든
scrape of all of that data to then build a robust company brochure.
데이터 긁어모음에서 하나 회사 브로슈어를 구축했죠
Uh, and, you know, as I say, this is like a toy starting version of a gigantic AI in a small way,
말씀드렸듯이 이건 거대한 인공지능의 장난감 버전과 같습니다 작은 방식으로요
because we're dividing up a bigger problem into smaller steps.
큰 문제를 작은 단계로 나누고 있으니까요
But I did want to impress upon you that this this is very applicable to many different kinds of business
하지만 여러분께 강조하고 싶은 건 이건 많은 종류의 비즈니스 문제에도 적용 가능하다는
problem, this kind of synthesizing information and then generating as a result of it.
겁니다 이런 종류의 정보를 통합하고 그 결과로 생성하는 거죠
Uh, and so you can imagine that you could do this to write marketing content to generate a product.
이렇게 제품을 생산하기 위한 마케팅 콘텐츠를 작성할 수 있어요
Uh, tutorial like a guide from product spec, uh, to create some personalized email content.
개인 맞춤형 이메일 콘텐츠를 만드는 튜토리얼 같은 거예요
By reading through a bunch of emails.
이메일을 많이 읽으면서요
So there are so many ways that you can imagine this kind of two step synthesize some data and summarize
방법은 아주 많아요 이런 2단계는 데이터를 합성하고 JSON에서 요약하는
it in JSON, and then use that as a way to build some kind of output.
거죠 일종의 출력을 구축하는 방법으로 사용해요
Many different applications of that.
다양한 응용 프로그램이 있죠
And so what I'd love to see you do is figure out a way to apply this to what you do day to day.
여러분이 매일 하는 일에 이걸 적용할 방법을 찾아보세요
And interesting commercial angle here.
흥미로운 상업적 각도예요
Uh, something that would allow you to think about your area of expertise, where you have the greatest
여러분이 가장 큰 영역 지식을 가진 자신의 전문 분야를 생각할 수 있는
domain knowledge.
그런 거요
And now given this new these, these skills you have, how could you put that to good use?
새로 얻은 기술을 어떻게 좋은 일에 쓸 건가요? TUZ
So have a think about that.
그러니 생각해 보세요
Feel free to bounce ideas off me at any point, and try and build some examples of that and put them
언제든 제 아이디어를 듣고 예를 들어서 깃허브에 올려 보세요
So you have some nice examples of using multiple calls to llms to synthesize information and generate
정보를 합성하고 콘텐츠를 생성하기 위해 llms에 다중 호출을 사용하는 좋은 예가
content.
있어요
I will see you for the next video.
그럼 다음 영상에서 만나요